<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<elements>
  <info>
    <name>Tome of Heroes — Magic Items</name>
    <description>Magic items from Tome of Heroes (mundane equipment excluded).</description>
    <update version="1.0.0">
      <file name="toh-items.xml" url="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/SageZeMage/aurora-toh/main/toh-items.xml" />
    </update>
  </info>

  <element name="Memento Mori" type="Magic Item" source="ToH" id="ID_ToH_ITEM_Memento_Mori">
    <description>As long as you have the memento mori in your possession, you don't require food, drink, or sleep. As an action, you can draw on all the stored memory at once and gain the effects of a potion of heroism. When the effect ends, the memento mori permanently loses its magic.</description>
    <sheet>
      <description>While you carry this, you don't need food, drink, or sleep. Once, as an action, gain the effects of a potion of heroism; the item then loses its magic.</description>
    </sheet>
    <setters>
      <set name="category">Magic Item</set>
      <set name="rarity">Uncommon</set>
      <set name="type">Wondrous Item</set>
    </setters>
  </element>

  <!-- HERB WORTS -->

  <element name="Alseid's Peony" type="Magic Item" source="ToH" id="ID_ToH_ITEM_Alseid_s_Peony">
    <description>Themes: guidance, secrets, and teamwork. Environments: in druidic circles, along animal paths, beside anthills.
Alseid's peony is a flowering plant with large, many-petaled blooms in shades of white, pink, and red with bright yellow centers. The flowers close at night or in cloudy conditions.

Minor Wort. As an action, you can tear an alseid peony bloom from its stem to summon a small, red-petaled creature called a bloomling. The bloomling uses the statistics of an awakened shrub and lasts for 1 hour or until destroyed. It is friendly to you and your companions. It rolls its own initiative and obeys your verbal commands (no action required). If you give no commands, it only defends itself. When the duration ends or it is destroyed, the bloomling crumbles into a pile of petals and sticks.

Ceremony Wort (3rd Level). While holding a handful of petals, you can spend 10 minutes concentrating on a specific location, then scatter the petals. They gently fall and land in the shape of an arrow pointing toward the imagined location. The petals scatter normally if the location doesn't exist or is on another plane. A clump of petals forms at the point of the arrow if a major obstacle lies between you and the location (such as a magical barrier, miles-long wall, desert, river, or similar). This wort requires 2 cuttings of alseid peony.

Cultivated Wort. A garden of alseid peonies cultivated for at least 4 weeks whispers secrets, lore, and rumors to those who listen. Each bloom repeats, in the original speaker’s language and voice, any words spoken within the garden since its first blooming. To bystanders, the whispers sound like wind through leaves; a creature can press an ear to a bloom to hear clearly. The peonies lack intelligence and repeat lies, truths, past, present, and future words without distinction, sometimes out of order for very old gardens. In addition, the zone of truth spell can't be cast inside or within 100 feet of the garden, though creatures that naturally distinguish truth from lies (such as planetars) know which whispers are lies.</description>
    <sheet>
      <description>Living peony of secrets. Minor: tear a bloom to summon an awakened-shrub bloomling for 1 hour. Ceremony: petal-arrow points toward a location, clumping if a major obstacle lies in the way. Cultivated: a 4-week garden repeats every word ever spoken within it and blocks zone of truth within 100 ft.</description>
    </sheet>
    <setters>
      <set name="category">Magic Item</set>
      <set name="rarity">Rare</set>
      <set name="type">Wondrous Item</set>
    </setters>
  </element>

  <element name="Asphodel" type="Magic Item" source="ToH" id="ID_ToH_ITEM_Asphodel">
    <description>Themes: death, sacrifice, and passage to and from the afterlife. Environments: battlefields, graveyards, hilltops.
Asphodel is a hardy, flowering plant with tufted leaves on elongated stems and white or yellow flowers.

Minor Wort. As an action, you can eat half of an asphodel bloom and place the rest in the mouth of a dead creature to see the last minute of that creature's life through its eyes. Afterwards, you must succeed on a DC 15 Constitution saving throw or gain one level of exhaustion.

Ceremony Wort (4th Level). You can bury a prized possession of at least uncommon rarity alongside asphodel to gain advantage on death saving throws for the next 4 hours. Burying the possession takes 1 minute. Up to five other creatures can participate, each burying their own possession for the same benefit. A creature can dig up its item at any time, ending the effect on that creature. Once a creature benefits from this wort, it can't do so again for 3 days. This wort requires burying the object beside a whole, healthy asphodel plant and doesn't require a specific number of cuttings.

Cultivated Wort (9th Level). A garden of asphodel cultivated for at least 12 weeks can return life to a creature that has been dead for no more than 1 year and 1 day and that didn't die of old age. After the body remains in the field for 1d8 hours, it is returned to life as if the resurrection spell had been cast on it. The entire field of asphodel then decays and withers, and asphodel can't be regrown there for 10 years and 1 day. The cultivator can set parameters on this effect (for example, only humanoids, or requiring a password to activate).</description>
    <sheet>
      <description>Funeral flower. Minor: see the last minute of a corpse’s life, risking 1 level of exhaustion (Con DC 15). Ceremony: bury a prized item to gain advantage on death saves for 4 hours. Cultivated: a 12-week garden can resurrect one non-old-age corpse (up to 1 year + 1 day dead), then withers for 10 years.</description>
    </sheet>
    <setters>
      <set name="category">Magic Item</set>
      <set name="rarity">Very Rare</set>
      <set name="type">Wondrous Item</set>
    </setters>
  </element>

  <element name="Bright Bishop Sage" type="Magic Item" source="ToH" id="ID_ToH_ITEM_Bright_Bishop_Sage">
    <description>Themes: protection, sanctuary, and purification. Environments: churches and temples, outside kitchen doors, near druidic circles.
Bright bishop sage is an evergreen shrub with woody stems, small blue and purple flowers, and short, broad, velvety leaves.

Minor Wort. As an action, you can burn a bundle of bright bishop sage to protect one creature, doorway, or object. A protected creature gains the benefits of protection from evil and good, except it is protected only from celestials, fiends, and undead.

Ceremony Wort. As an action, you can sprinkle chopped sage into or onto up to six plates, bowls, or glasses of nonmagical food or drink. The food and drink are purified and rendered free of poison and disease. This wort requires 2 cuttings of bright bishop sage.

Cultivated Wort (9th Level). A garden of bright bishop sage cultivated for at least 8 weeks is protected by heavenly magic. Aberrations, elementals, fey, fiends, and undead can't enter the garden or a space within 15 feet of it, and dead bodies interred in or within 15 feet of the garden can't be turned into undead.</description>
    <sheet>
      <description>Holy sage. Minor: burn a bundle to protect a creature, doorway, or object as protection from evil and good vs celestials/fiends/undead. Ceremony: purify up to 6 servings of food/drink. Cultivated: 8-week garden blocks aberrations, elementals, fey, fiends, and undead within 15 ft, and prevents corpses there from becoming undead.</description>
    </sheet>
    <setters>
      <set name="category">Magic Item</set>
      <set name="rarity">Uncommon</set>
      <set name="type">Wondrous Item</set>
    </setters>
  </element>

  <element name="Champion's Lavender" type="Magic Item" source="ToH" id="ID_ToH_ITEM_Champion_s_Lavender">
    <description>Themes: devotion, swift healing, and truth. Environments: near shrines, where vows were honored, after steadfast vigils.
Champion's lavender is a flowering shrub with narrow leaves and blue, violet, or lilac flowers growing on tall spikelike stems.

Minor Wort. As an action, you can press a sprig to a creature's wound to hasten healing or ease fatigue. The target can immediately spend one of its Hit Dice to regain hit points as if at the end of a rest, or it can make a DC 13 Constitution saving throw to recover from one level of exhaustion on a success.

Ceremony Wort (3rd Level). If you spend 10 minutes chanting and walking the perimeter of an area no larger than a 40-foot cube while waving a lit, smoking bundle of champion's lavender, you create a ward against unseen intruders. Using a censer to concentrate the smoke allows an 80-foot cube instead. The ward lasts 8 hours. While an invisible creature is in the warded area, it is outlined in a purple glow, and each creature present during the warding is mentally alerted to its presence.

Cultivated Wort (5th Level). A garden of champion's lavender cultivated for at least 4 weeks becomes a shrine to truth, marking trespassing oathbreakers and deceivers. While in the garden, any creature that has broken a vow or committed a deliberate deception that caused another great harm is marked with a dim purple symbol or rune chosen by the gardener. The mark remains until the creature leaves. It does not appear if the creature has found justice or redemption, such as paying fines, serving the community, or atoning at a temple. The garden ignores minor or unintentional deceptions.</description>
    <sheet>
      <description>Lavender of oaths. Minor: touch to let a creature spend a Hit Die or attempt to remove 1 level of exhaustion (Con DC 13). Ceremony: lavender smoke wards a 40–80 ft cube, outlining invisible creatures and alerting those who helped ward. Cultivated: 4-week garden marks serious oathbreakers and harmful deceivers with a purple sign until they leave or atone.</description>
    </sheet>
    <setters>
      <set name="category">Magic Item</set>
      <set name="rarity">Uncommon</set>
      <set name="type">Wondrous Item</set>
    </setters>
  </element>

  <element name="Chaunic Clover" type="Magic Item" source="ToH" id="ID_ToH_ITEM_Chaunic_Clover">
    <description>Themes: prosperity, luck, and risk. Environments: at the end of rainbows, near fairy circles, near sites of major breakthroughs or successes.
Chaunic clover is a low-growing, sprawling plant with leaves in groups of three or four and small, spiky flowers in white, purple, or yellow.

Minor Wort. As an action, you can place a sprig of chaunic clover into a pouch containing up to 99 copper or silver pieces and roll a d100. If you roll higher than the number of coins in the pouch, the number of coins doubles. If you roll 100, the number of coins doubles and each becomes a gold piece. If you roll a 1, all the coins are destroyed and a fey creature on the same plane learns of your failed attempt and takes an interest in you. The sprig is destroyed either way.

Ceremony Wort. As an action, you can place a pot, kettle, or cup with a sprig of chaunic clover inside under the shade of an old tree to summon a magic cauldron for 10 minutes. The first time you do so, the cauldron is empty and becomes bound to you. Each later use summons the same cauldron from a tiny demiplane accessible only by a wish spell when not summoned. It can hold any number of coins, and only coins. You can dismiss it early as an action. If you die, the cauldron becomes nonmagical and appears in the shade of one of the trees where you previously summoned it, holding whatever coins it contained. If you return to life and use this wort again, you bind a new, empty cauldron. This wort requires 1 cutting of chaunic clover.

Cultivated Wort (8th Level). A garden of chaunic clover cultivated for at least 4 weeks blesses the land with abundance. Within 1 mile, plants grow lush and disease-resistant, crops double their yield, and plant creatures are 60 percent more likely to be neutral or friendly instead of hostile.</description>
    <sheet>
      <description>Fey-luck clover. Minor: gamble up to 99 c/s—on a high d100 you double the coins, on 100 you double and upgrade to gold, on 1 you lose them all and attract a fey’s notice. Ceremony: summon a personal extradimensional coin-only cauldron. Cultivated: 4-week garden doubles crop yields and improves plant health and temperament within 1 mile.</description>
    </sheet>
    <setters>
      <set name="category">Magic Item</set>
      <set name="rarity">Very Rare</set>
      <set name="type">Wondrous Item</set>
    </setters>
  </element>

  <element name="Emperor's Garlic" type="Magic Item" source="ToH" id="ID_ToH_ITEM_Emperor_s_Garlic">
    <description>Themes: authority, immunity, and sight beyond sight. Environments: among wildflowers, near ancient trees, in ruins or lairs once used by wise beings.
Emperor's garlic is a flowering plant with a tall stem from a bulb, flat blade-like leaves, and spherical clusters of pink or purple flowers.

Minor Wort. You can eat a raw clove as an action to gain resistance to poison damage and advantage on saving throws against being poisoned for 1 hour; however, you have disadvantage on Charisma (Deception) and Charisma (Persuasion) checks for the duration. If you already have resistance to poison damage, you gain immunity instead.

Ceremony Wort (3rd Level). Using a bulb of emperor's garlic as a focus, you and at least two other characters can perform a 1-minute exorcism on a possessed target, each maintaining concentration while within 30 feet. The exorcism fails if no one maintains concentration or all are more than 30 feet from the target; if it fails, you can't attempt another exorcism for 24 hours. At the end of the duration, if at least one character maintained concentration, the target is freed from possession as if by the break enchantment effect of dispel evil and good. The garlic is consumed. This wort requires 4 cuttings.

Cultivated Wort (5th Level). A garden of emperor's garlic cultivated for at least 4 weeks protects the area from undead. An undead creature that starts its turn inside or within 100 feet of the garden must succeed on a Charisma saving throw or be turned.</description>
    <sheet>
      <description>Imperial garlic. Minor: eat a clove for 1 hour of poison resistance (or immunity if you already had resistance) and advantage vs poison, but disadvantage on Deception/Persuasion. Ceremony: multi-caster 1-minute exorcism that functions as dispel evil and good (break enchantment). Cultivated: 4-week garden forces nearby undead (within 100 ft) to save or be turned each round.</description>
    </sheet>
    <setters>
      <set name="category">Magic Item</set>
      <set name="rarity">Rare</set>
      <set name="type">Wondrous Item</set>
    </setters>
  </element>

  <element name="Far Traveler's Freesia" type="Magic Item" source="ToH" id="ID_ToH_ITEM_Far_Traveler_s_Freesia">
    <description>Themes: friendship, trust, purity, and innocence. Environments: shorelines, crossroads, outside inns, taverns, and trading posts.
Far traveler's freesia is a flowering plant with long, narrow leaves and conical flowers in shades of white, red, and yellow.

Minor Wort. As an action, you can give a freesia sprig as a gift to a creature to win it over. If the target is hostile toward you, it must succeed on a Wisdom saving throw or become indifferent toward you. A beast with Intelligence 3 or lower has disadvantage on the save.

Ceremony Wort. If you soak freesia in a bowl of holy water, you can perform a 10-minute ritual of protection on a number of creatures equal to 1 + your proficiency bonus, brushing the water on their brows. Each target has advantage on ability checks and saving throws against exhaustion and gains 1d6 temporary hit points for 8 hours. This wort requires 2 cuttings.

Cultivated Wort. A garden of far traveler’s freesia cultivated for at least 4 weeks attracts friendly moths and butterflies. Any that feed on the freesia for at least 24 hours gain Intelligence 6 and can speak Common and one other language known by the gardener. They are at least indifferent to other creatures in the garden and usually willing to help with simple tasks that don't take them away from the garden for more than 24 hours.</description>
    <sheet>
      <description>Wanderer’s freesia. Minor: gift it to potentially turn a hostile creature indifferent (beasts Int 3 or lower have disadvantage). Ceremony: holy-water freesia blesses 1 + PB creatures with advantage vs exhaustion and 1d6 temp HP for 8 hours. Cultivated: 4-week garden grants local moths and butterflies Int 6 and speech (Common + one language), making them helpful guides.</description>
    </sheet>
    <setters>
      <set name="category">Magic Item</set>
      <set name="rarity">Uncommon</set>
      <set name="type">Wondrous Item</set>
    </setters>
  </element>

  <element name="Fiery Snapdragon" type="Magic Item" source="ToH" id="ID_ToH_ITEM_Fiery_Snapdragon">
    <description>Themes: fire, strength, and presence. Environments: areas scarred by forest fires, scorch marks from fire magic, temples of sun deities.
Fiery snapdragon is a flowering plant with tall, narrow stalks and spiraled leaves. Its flowers resemble gaping dragon maws in yellow, pink, or red.

Minor Wort. As an action, you can place a sprig into the flame of a lit torch to grant any creature carrying that torch resistance to fire damage. The torch's remaining duration becomes 10 minutes if it was longer. A creature carrying the torch can use a bonus action to extinguish it and gain immunity to fire damage until the start of its next turn; the torch then crumbles to dust.

Ceremony Wort (5th Level). If you create a bonfire laden with fiery snapdragon, you can perform a 10-minute ritual of strength on one creature within 10 feet of the bonfire. At the end of the ritual, the target’s Strength score becomes 25 for 1 hour. This wort requires 4 cuttings.

Cultivated Wort (9th Level). A garden of fiery snapdragon cultivated for at least 4 weeks repels draconic invaders. A dragon that starts its turn inside or within 150 feet of the garden must make a Wisdom saving throw or be turned as if by a cleric’s Channel Divinity: Turn Undead. Other draconic creatures (such as chimeras or kobolds) can also be turned but have advantage on the save.</description>
    <sheet>
      <description>Dragon-flame flowers. Minor: torch + sprig = fire resistance; snuff the torch (bonus action) to gain 1 round of fire immunity and destroy the torch. Ceremony: 10-minute bonfire ritual raises a creature’s Strength to 25 for 1 hour. Cultivated: 4-week garden forces nearby dragons (150 ft) to save or be turned; other draconic creatures save with advantage.</description>
    </sheet>
    <setters>
      <set name="category">Magic Item</set>
      <set name="rarity">Rare</set>
      <set name="type">Wondrous Item</set>
    </setters>
  </element>

  <element name="Gazing Hydrangea" type="Magic Item" source="ToH" id="ID_ToH_ITEM_Gazing_Hydrangea">
    <description>Themes: unbinding, mental protection, and psychic strength. Environments: desert oases, near theaters and stages, outside windows facing mirrors.
Gazing hydrangea is a small shrub with short, broad leaves and hemispherical bundles of tiny inner flowers ringed by larger pink, blue, or purple blossoms.

Minor Wort. As an action, you can crush and toss hydrangea petals at a creature you can see within 10 feet. The target must succeed on a Charisma saving throw or lose attunement to one randomly chosen magic item it is carrying or wearing.

Ceremony Wort. You can craft a flower crown from gazing hydrangea blooms and stems over 1 hour. While wearing the crown, a creature has resistance to psychic damage and its thoughts can't be read by spells such as detect thoughts. Each crown requires 2 cuttings and lasts 8 hours.

Cultivated Wort (4th Level). A garden of gazing hydrangea cultivated for at least 4 weeks strengthens divination. A divination spell cast as a ritual within the garden requires no components, and its duration is doubled.</description>
    <sheet>
      <description>Mind-ward hydrangea. Minor: throw petals to force a creature (Charisma save) to drop attunement to a random item. Ceremony: 1-hour flower crown grants psychic resistance and blocks mind-reading (e.g. detect thoughts) for 8 hours. Cultivated: 4-week garden makes ritual divinations free of components and doubles their duration.</description>
    </sheet>
    <setters>
      <set name="category">Magic Item</set>
      <set name="rarity">Very Rare</set>
      <set name="type">Wondrous Item</set>
    </setters>
  </element>

  <element name="Hoary Valerian" type="Magic Item" source="ToH" id="ID_ToH_ITEM_Hoary_Valerian">
    <description>Themes: dreams private and shared, relaxation, and sleep. Environments: campsites, near forest altars, where enchantments were cast.
Hoary valerian is a tall plant with narrow leaves in close pairs along frond-like stalks, and long stems topped with clusters of tiny flowers.

Minor Wort. As an action, you can crush the leaves of a sprig and blow them at a creature you can see within 10 feet. The target must succeed on a Constitution saving throw or fall unconscious for 1d10 minutes. The effect ends if the creature takes damage or someone uses an action to wake it.

Ceremony Wort (9th Level). If you steep hoary valerian roots in hot water for 1 minute, you can pour the liquid in a ring of up to 20-foot radius. Small bushes sprout along the ring in 10 minutes and last for 4 hours. A creature that rests inside the ring finishes its long rest in 4 hours rather than 8 and regains twice as many Hit Dice at the end of the long rest. This wort requires 4 cuttings.

Cultivated Wort. A garden of hoary valerian cultivated for 4 weeks causes humanoids who sleep within 1 mile to share lucid dreams at least once per week. The dreams are usually peaceful, but sometimes contain minor prophetic elements.</description>
    <sheet>
      <description>Dream valerian. Minor: blow crushed leaves for a sleep effect (Con save or unconscious 1d10 minutes, ending on damage or being shaken awake). Ceremony: 4-hour “super long rest” ring that doubles Hit Dice recovery (9th-level wort). Cultivated: 4-week garden links local sleepers into occasional shared, sometimes prophetic, lucid dreams.</description>
    </sheet>
    <setters>
      <set name="category">Magic Item</set>
      <set name="rarity">Uncommon</set>
      <set name="type">Wondrous Item</set>
    </setters>
  </element>

  <element name="Merchant's Mint" type="Magic Item" source="ToH" id="ID_ToH_ITEM_Merchant_s_Mint">
    <description>Themes: abundance, communication, and honorable deals. Environments: caravan tracks, near grain silos, where treaties were signed.
Merchant's mint is a low-growing, sprawling plant with square stems and paired serrated leaves, bearing clustered flowers from white to purple.

Minor Wort. As an action, you can place a sprig beneath your tongue to cast comprehend languages on yourself. The sprig must remain in your mouth for the spell’s duration; spitting it out ends the spell.

Ceremony Wort. When you and another creature are at odds, you can write both names on a page, wrap the page with two sprigs of merchant’s mint, and burn the bundle to summon a draconic arbitrator, typically a pseudodragon (or a pact drake, at the GM’s option). It can speak Common and Draconic, listens to both sides, seeks an amicable resolution, and fights only in self-defense. It remains for up to 1 hour or until the dispute is clearly no longer being pursued in good faith, at the GM’s discretion. This wort requires 2 cuttings.

Cultivated Wort. A garden of merchant’s mint cultivated for at least 12 weeks guards nearby lands against disease and famine. Within 5 miles, fields never become barren, harvests are always abundant, and livestock grazing there never falls ill.</description>
    <sheet>
      <description>Trader’s mint. Minor: chew a sprig to self-cast comprehend languages while it stays under your tongue. Ceremony: burn names + mint to summon a pseudodragon-style arbitrator for up to 1 hour. Cultivated: 12-week garden keeps fields fertile, harvests rich, and grazing livestock disease-free within 5 miles.</description>
    </sheet>
    <setters>
      <set name="category">Magic Item</set>
      <set name="rarity">Rare</set>
      <set name="type">Wondrous Item</set>
    </setters>
  </element>

  <element name="Mirthy Hops" type="Magic Item" source="ToH" id="ID_ToH_ITEM_Mirthy_Hops">
    <description>Themes: joy, fellowship, and humor. Environments: near wheat fields, campsites, outside drinking halls and taverns.
Mirthy hops is a tall climbing vine with dark green heart-shaped leaves and fragrant pale green cones.

Minor Wort. As an action, you can eat a bud to triple your jump distance for 1 minute. Your jumps look wild and chaotic; any creature that sees you jump must make a Wisdom saving throw or burst into giggles until the start of your next turn. A giggling creature has disadvantage on its next attack roll or skill check. On a success, the creature is immune to mirthy-hops giggles for 24 hours.

Ceremony Wort (11th Level). If you spend 1 minute singing a drinking song while holding a pitcher of ale with buds of mirthy hops floating in it, you can call upon the fey. At the end of the minute, you summon a fey as though casting conjure fey. Unless immediate danger threatens you or the fey, it requires you to play a drinking game before it will obey commands or agree to service; the GM determines the nature of the game. This wort requires 3 cuttings.

Cultivated Wort. A garden of mirthy hops cultivated for at least 4 weeks protects nearby folk from overwhelming terror. Within 1 mile, creatures have advantage on saving throws against being frightened, and creatures attempting to use Charisma (Intimidation) checks have disadvantage.</description>
    <sheet>
      <description>Hops of hilarity. Minor: eat a bud to triple your jump distance for 1 minute; observers must save or giggle and suffer disadvantage on their next attack/check. Ceremony: 11th-level ritual summons a conjure fey ally that demands a drinking game first. Cultivated: 4-week garden grants advantage vs fear and disadvantage on Intimidation within 1 mile.</description>
    </sheet>
    <setters>
      <set name="category">Magic Item</set>
      <set name="rarity">Rare</set>
      <set name="type">Wondrous Item</set>
    </setters>
  </element>

  <element name="Nimbus Daffodil" type="Magic Item" source="ToH" id="ID_ToH_ITEM_Nimbus_Daffodil">
    <description>Themes: change, the cycle of seasons, and weather. Environments: bottoms of waterfalls, fresh rain puddles, riverbanks.
Nimbus daffodil is a bulb plant with a central branching stem, long narrow leaves, and a drooping, two-layered trumpet flower in yellow and white.

Minor Wort. As an action, you can break a daffodil stem in two to create a 20-foot-radius sphere of fog centered on you, functioning as a fog cloud spell.

Ceremony Wort (6th Level). If you spend 10 minutes dancing outdoors while holding a wand of bundled nimbus daffodils, you can summon rain. A cylindrical cloud (10 feet tall, 120-foot radius) appears centered on a point 100 feet above you. For 1 minute, plants in the area are watered, open containers fill with fresh water, and any spell cast by a caster within the rain that creates or controls water, clouds, or weather has its range or duration (caster’s choice) doubled. If the spell requires concentration, concentration is still required. If four other 6th-level or higher creatures, each with their own wand, use a reaction to join your dance, the rain instead appears on initiative count 20 of the next round, skipping the 10-minute duration. This wort requires 3 cuttings.

Cultivated Wort (7th Level). A garden of nimbus daffodil cultivated for 5 weeks protects surrounding lands from harsh weather. Within 5 miles, skies are rarely overcast, sunlight is gentle but still harmful to creatures vulnerable to it, and seasonally appropriate light rain or snow falls each morning.</description>
    <sheet>
      <description>Weather daffodil. Minor: snap a stem to cast a 20-ft radius fog cloud centered on you. Ceremony: 6th-level rain-summoning dance that buffs water/weather spells’ range or duration and waters the land. Cultivated: 5-week garden keeps a 5-mile area pleasantly sunny with gentle daily precipitation (still lethal to sunlight-vulnerable creatures).</description>
    </sheet>
    <setters>
      <set name="category">Magic Item</set>
      <set name="rarity">Uncommon</set>
      <set name="type">Wondrous Item</set>
    </setters>
  </element>

  <element name="Old Elvish Rose" type="Magic Item" source="ToH" id="ID_ToH_ITEM_Old_Elvish_Rose">
    <description>Themes: contradictions, grace, and peaceful intentions. Environments: near fey homes, where proposals were made, around forgotten towers.
Old elvish rose is a shrub with alternating leaves and sickle-shaped thorns. Its cup-shaped blooms come in white, pink, yellow, or red.

Minor Wort. As an action, you can draw an old elvish rose across the blade of a slashing weapon to cause thorns to sprout from it for 1 minute. While thorned, the weapon deals an extra 1d6 piercing damage on a hit.

Ceremony Wort (2nd Level). If you spend 10 minutes drawing a bath infused with elvish roses, a creature can soak for 1 hour (during a rest) to ward away fear and unwanted advances. Until it finishes its next rest, it has advantage on saving throws against being charmed and frightened. If it already has advantage against one of these conditions when it exits the bath, it instead has immunity to that condition. This wort requires 2 cuttings.

Cultivated Wort (9th Level). A garden of old elvish roses cultivated for at least 26 weeks quells strong emotions. A hostile humanoid or beast that enters or starts its turn inside the garden or within 100 feet of it must succeed on a Charisma saving throw or become indifferent toward creatures it was previously hostile toward. The indifference ends if the creature or its allies are harmed. In addition, any effect that charms or frightens humanoids or beasts is suppressed while the creature remains in the garden; it resumes when the creature leaves if the effect's duration hasn't expired. This functions like calm emotions.</description>
    <sheet>
      <description>Elven rose. Minor: swipe across a slashing weapon to add 1d6 piercing damage for 1 minute. Ceremony: rose-infused bath grants advantage vs charm and fright (or immunity if you already had advantage) until your next rest. Cultivated: 26-week garden functions as a large calm emotions zone and can force hostiles in/near it to become indifferent on a Charisma save.</description>
    </sheet>
    <setters>
      <set name="category">Magic Item</set>
      <set name="rarity">Very Rare</set>
      <set name="type">Wondrous Item</set>
    </setters>
  </element>

  <element name="Wolfsbane" type="Magic Item" source="ToH" id="ID_ToH_ITEM_Wolfsbane">
    <description>Themes: lycanthropy, transformation, and the moon. Environments: secluded groves, planar borders with Shadow, sites of forced shapechanging.
Wolfsbane is a poisonous flowering plant with dark green palm-like leaves and tall stems crowned with hoodlike flowers in blues, purples, whites, yellows, or pinks.

Minor Wort. As an action, you can crush and sprinkle petals over a creature or object that has been turned to stone or otherwise transformed (such as by polymorph). The target immediately reverts to its original form. An unwilling creature can make a Charisma saving throw to resist.

Ceremony Wort (7th Level). If you soak petals in a bowl of shallow water beneath a full moon for 10 minutes, you can imbue them with lunar power. You and up to five other creatures can consume the petals to cast polymorph on yourselves, each transforming into a dire wolf but retaining your own Intelligence, Wisdom, and Charisma scores. The transformation lasts until dawn’s first light touches a transformed creature, the creature drops to 0 hit points or dies, or some other effect forces it to revert. This wort requires 3 cuttings.

Cultivated Wort (5th Level). A garden of wolfsbane cultivated for at least 8 weeks can cleanse lycanthropy. A creature afflicted with lycanthropy that rests in the garden is cured—but during the rest, it must make death saving throws as the magic attacks the curse. If it fails three death saves before succeeding on three, it dies, but the lycanthropy is removed. A creature born with lycanthropy (inherited rather than inflicted) is cured only if it is willing, remains in the garden for 1 week, and survives the death save sequence during its first rest in the garden.</description>
    <sheet>
      <description>Moonbane. Minor: petals forcibly revert petrified or polymorphed creatures/objects (Charisma save to resist if unwilling). Ceremony: 7th-level full-moon ritual lets up to 6 creatures polymorph into dire wolves while keeping their mental stats until dawn or 0 HP. Cultivated: 8-week garden can cure lycanthropy, but the patient must survive death saves during treatment or die as the curse is ripped out.</description>
    </sheet>
    <setters>
      <set name="category">Magic Item</set>
      <set name="rarity">Very Rare</set>
      <set name="type">Wondrous Item</set>
    </setters>
  </element>

  <!-- NON-HERB ITEMS -->

  <element name="Argent Mantle" type="Magic Item" source="ToH" id="ID_ToH_ITEM_Argent_Mantle">
    <description>Often reserved for ranking knights of dogmatic or monastic orders, this finely made hood-and-shoulder mantle endows the wearer with exceptional battlefield, statecraft, and leadership presence. As a bonus action, you can speak a command word to cause a nimbus of golden light to surround your head. This nimbus sheds bright light in a 20-foot radius and dim light for an additional 20 feet. Friendly creatures in the bright light have advantage on initiative checks and can't be surprised except when incapacitated. The nimbus lasts until you use a bonus action to speak the command word again or remove the mantle.

Endearing Leader. While wearing this mantle, you can use an action to increase your Charisma score to 20 for 10 minutes. This has no effect if your Charisma is already 20 or higher. Once used, this property can't be used again until the next dawn.</description>
    <sheet>
      <description>Knightly mantle (armor). Bonus action: create a 20-ft bright / 20-ft dim golden nimbus; allies in the bright light have advantage on initiative and can’t be surprised unless incapacitated. 1/day, action: set your Charisma to 20 for 10 minutes (no effect if already 20+).</description>
    </sheet>
    <setters>
      <set name="category">Magic Armor</set>
      <set name="rarity">Rare</set>
      <set name="type">Armor</set>
    </setters>
  </element>

  <element name="Beads of Contemplation" type="Magic Item" source="ToH" id="ID_ToH_ITEM_Beads_of_Contemplation">
    <description>This strand of eight wooden beads, each carved with geometric patterns, hangs from a stout cord. The beads store ki you place into them until you draw it back out. The strand can store up to 8 ki points. At the end of a rest, you can touch the beads and expend ki equal to half your proficiency bonus to store that many points in the beads.

While wearing or carrying the beads, you can use a bonus action to remove any number of ki points from the beads, regaining that amount of ki and freeing space in the strand.</description>
    <sheet>
      <description>Ki-storage beads (max 8 ki). After a rest, you can invest ki equal to half your PB. Bonus action: pull any amount of stored ki back into yourself.</description>
    </sheet>
    <setters>
      <set name="category">Magic Item</set>
      <set name="rarity">Uncommon</set>
      <set name="type">Wondrous Item</set>
    </setters>
  </element>

  <element name="Bloodspeed Elixir" type="Magic Item" source="ToH" id="ID_ToH_ITEM_Bloodspeed_Elixir">
    <description>This murky crimson potion smells of ozone and has a thick, sludge-like consistency. When you drink it, your speed triples for 1 minute, but if you take the Dash action during that time, you take 2d6 poison damage as your body is pushed beyond its limits.</description>
    <sheet>
      <description>Sludgy red potion. For 1 minute your speed is tripled, but each time you Dash you take 2d6 poison damage.</description>
    </sheet>
    <setters>
      <set name="category">Magic Item</set>
      <set name="rarity">Rare</set>
      <set name="type">Potion</set>
    </setters>
  </element>

  <element name="Campaign Field Tent" type="Magic Item" source="ToH" id="ID_ToH_ITEM_Campaign_Field_Tent">
    <description>This 1-inch cloth cube unfolds into a sturdy field tent. As an action, you can place the cube on the ground and speak its command word, causing it to rapidly grow into a canvas tent 15 feet on a side and 10 feet high, with open or closed sides (your choice). It remains until you use an action to speak the command word to dismiss it, which only works if the tent is empty.

The tent is firmly fixed to the ground, even on bare stone, a ship's deck, or loose sand, and can't be tipped over. Each creature in the space where the tent appears must make a DC 15 Dexterity saving throw, taking 5d10 bludgeoning damage and being pushed to the nearest unoccupied space next to the tent on a failed save, or half damage and the same push on a success. Unattended objects take this damage and are pushed automatically.

The tent has 50 hit points, immunity to nonmagical attacks (except siege weapons), and resistance to all other damage. Inside are a small table and chair and five simple cloth-and-wood beds. It can hold up to six Medium or smaller creatures. A creature that finishes a rest in the tent regains double the hit points from Hit Dice it spends and reduces its exhaustion level by 2 instead of 1. In addition, while resting inside it, a creature has advantage on saving throws against disease and poison.</description>
    <sheet>
      <description>Collapsible magic field tent cube. Action: deploy 15×15×10 ft tent (DC 15 Dex save vs 5d10 bludgeoning for creatures/objects in its space). 50 HP, immune to nonmagical attacks (except siege), resistant to others. Holds 6 Medium creatures; resting inside doubles Hit Die healing, reduces exhaustion by 2, and grants advantage vs disease/poison.</description>
    </sheet>
    <setters>
      <set name="category">Magic Item</set>
      <set name="rarity">Rare</set>
      <set name="type">Wondrous Item</set>
    </setters>
  </element>

  <element name="Cestus +1" type="Magic Item" source="ToH" id="ID_ToH_ITEM_Cestus_1">
    <description>These leather hand wraps are padded across the knuckles. While wearing them, you have a +1 bonus to attack and damage rolls made with your unarmed strikes.</description>
    <sheet>
      <description>Padded wraps. Your unarmed strikes gain a +1 bonus to attack and damage rolls.</description>
    </sheet>
    <setters>
      <set name="category">Magic Item</set>
      <set name="rarity">Uncommon</set>
      <set name="type">Wondrous Item</set>
    </setters>
  </element>

  <element name="Cestus +2" type="Magic Item" source="ToH" id="ID_ToH_ITEM_Cestus_2">
    <description>These leather hand wraps are padded across the knuckles. While wearing them, you have a +2 bonus to attack and damage rolls made with your unarmed strikes.</description>
    <sheet>
      <description>Padded wraps. Your unarmed strikes gain a +2 bonus to attack and damage rolls.</description>
    </sheet>
    <setters>
      <set name="category">Magic Item</set>
      <set name="rarity">Rare</set>
      <set name="type">Wondrous Item</set>
    </setters>
  </element>

  <element name="Cestus +3" type="Magic Item" source="ToH" id="ID_ToH_ITEM_Cestus_3">
    <description>These leather hand wraps are padded across the knuckles. While wearing them, you have a +3 bonus to attack and damage rolls made with your unarmed strikes.</description>
    <sheet>
      <description>Padded wraps. Your unarmed strikes gain a +3 bonus to attack and damage rolls.</description>
    </sheet>
    <setters>
      <set name="category">Magic Item</set>
      <set name="rarity">Very Rare</set>
      <set name="type">Wondrous Item</set>
    </setters>
  </element>

  <element name="Chain Cilice" type="Magic Item" source="ToH" id="ID_ToH_ITEM_Chain_Cilice">
    <description>This bracelet of spiked chain fits around an ankle, wrist, or thigh. While wearing it, you can use an action to speak its command word, causing it to tighten into your flesh and dealing 1d6 piercing damage to you at the start of each of your turns until you use a bonus action to end the effect. If you have the Ki class feature or another source of ki points, you regain 1 ki point for every 5 damage the cilice deals to you.

If the cilice would reduce you to 0 hit points, you instead drop to 1 hit point and the effect ends. Once this happens, the cilice can't be activated again until the next dawn.</description>
    <sheet>
      <description>Self-punishing chain. Action: activate to take 1d6 piercing damage at the start of each of your turns until ended (bonus action). For every 5 damage dealt, you regain 1 ki. If it would drop you to 0 HP, you stay at 1 HP and the effect ends; then can’t be used again until dawn.</description>
    </sheet>
    <setters>
      <set name="category">Magic Item</set>
      <set name="rarity">Uncommon</set>
      <set name="type">Wondrous Item</set>
    </setters>
  </element>

  <element name="Cloak of Tentacles" type="Magic Item" source="ToH" id="ID_ToH_ITEM_Cloak_of_Tentacles">
    <description>This cloak settles around your shoulders like a living, writhing thing, at once warm and icy cold against your skin.

Shimmering Skin. While wearing the cloak, you can use an action to expose its shimmering inner lining. Each creature within 10 feet of you that can see you must make a DC 15 Wisdom saving throw or be incapacitated until the end of its next turn. Once you use this property, you can't use it again until the next dawn.

Writhing Tentacles. While wearing the cloak, you can use a bonus action to command it to sprout four writhing tentacles for 1 minute. When a creature within 10 feet hits you with a melee attack, one tentacle lashes out and makes a melee attack with a +7 bonus to hit. On a hit, it deals 2d10 bludgeoning damage and that tentacle becomes inert. When the duration ends or all four tentacles have become inert, this property can't be used again until the next dawn.</description>
    <sheet>
      <description>Tentacled cloak. 1/day action: flash the inner lining to force nearby creatures (10 ft, sight) to save vs DC 15 Wis or be incapacitated until end of their next turn. 1/day bonus action: sprout 4 reactive tentacles for 1 minute; on each melee hit against you within 10 ft, a tentacle counterattacks (+7, 2d10 bludgeoning) then goes inert.</description>
    </sheet>
    <setters>
      <set name="category">Magic Item</set>
      <set name="rarity">Rare</set>
      <set name="type">Wondrous Item</set>
    </setters>
  </element>

  <element name="Deepstone Cestus" type="Magic Item" source="ToH" id="ID_ToH_ITEM_Deepstone_Cestus">
    <description>These leather hand wraps are fitted with round, flat stones etched with runes. While you wear them, your ki save DC increases by 2.</description>
    <sheet>
      <description>Rune-stone wraps. While worn, your ki save DC increases by 2.</description>
    </sheet>
    <setters>
      <set name="category">Magic Item</set>
      <set name="rarity">Very Rare</set>
      <set name="type">Wondrous Item</set>
    </setters>
  </element>

  <element name="Esquire's Rowels" type="Magic Item" source="ToH" id="ID_ToH_ITEM_Esquire_s_Rowels">
    <description>These silver-chased spurs aid mounted travel. While riding a mount and wearing the rowels, you gain a +1 bonus to initiative rolls, and your mount's AC increases by 2. In addition, while riding your mount with these spurs, you and your mount have advantage on Constitution saving throws against exhaustion from traveling more than 8 hours in a day.</description>
    <sheet>
      <description>Silver spurs. While mounted, you gain +1 to initiative, your mount’s AC +2, and both of you have advantage on Con saves vs travel-induced exhaustion (over 8 hours).</description>
    </sheet>
    <setters>
      <set name="category">Magic Item</set>
      <set name="rarity">Rare</set>
      <set name="type">Wondrous Item</set>
    </setters>
  </element>

  <element name="Fletcher's Retort Gloves" type="Magic Item" source="ToH" id="ID_ToH_ITEM_Fletcher_s_Retort_Gloves">
    <description>These gloves empower your Deflect Missiles reaction. When you use Deflect Missiles while wearing them, you can spend 1 ki point to reduce the damage by 1d10 + your Dexterity modifier + twice your monk level instead of the normal amount. If you reduce the damage to 0 this way and spend 1 ki point to throw the missile, the attack has a normal range of 30 feet and a long range of 120 feet.

In addition, when a friendly creature within 5 feet of you is hit by a ranged weapon attack while you wear these gloves, you can use Deflect Missiles to deflect or catch the missile as if you had been the target.</description>
    <sheet>
      <description>Monk archer’s gloves. When you Deflect Missiles, you can spend 1 ki to reduce damage by 1d10 + Dex mod + 2× monk level, and if you throw it back (1 ki) you get a 30/120 ft range. You can also Deflect Missiles for adjacent allies hit by ranged weapon attacks.</description>
    </sheet>
    <setters>
      <set name="category">Magic Item</set>
      <set name="rarity">Rare</set>
      <set name="type">Wondrous Item</set>
    </setters>
  </element>

  <element name="Giantstrike Cestus" type="Magic Item" source="ToH" id="ID_ToH_ITEM_Giantstrike_Cestus">
    <description>These leather hand wraps are fitted with rune-engraved iron plates. While wearing them, your Martial Arts die for unarmed strikes is one die size higher than normal.</description>
    <sheet>
      <description>Heavy rune wraps. Increases your Martial Arts die by one step while making unarmed strikes.</description>
    </sheet>
    <setters>
      <set name="category">Magic Item</set>
      <set name="rarity">Very Rare</set>
      <set name="type">Wondrous Item</set>
    </setters>
  </element>

  <!-- HEARTGLOW LANTERNS -->

  <element name="Deadbane Heartglow Lantern" type="Magic Item" source="ToH" id="ID_ToH_ITEM_Deadbane_Heartglow_Lantern">
    <description>Fashioned from a single piece of specially grown hexagonal crystal in a metal frame, a heartglow lantern produces light without flame or fuel, making it ideal in places with limited air. While holding the lantern, you can use an action to speak its command word and cause it to shed bright light in a 20-foot radius and dim light for an additional 20 feet. The light lasts until you use a bonus action to repeat the command word or release the lantern.

Any creature touching the lantern can use an action to infuse it with vitality. That creature’s hit point maximum is reduced by an amount equal to its proficiency bonus, and the lantern gains that many charges. This reduction lasts until the creature finishes a rest. A lantern can hold any number of charges from any number of creatures, but each individual creature can infuse it only once between long rests.

Deadbane. While holding this lantern, you can use an action and expend 1 or more charges to have the lantern detect undead for 1 hour. When an undead is within 20 feet of the lantern, its light shifts to blue, becoming brighter the closer the undead is. For each charge beyond the first, the effect’s duration increases by 30 minutes, and the distance at which undead are detected increases by 5 feet (this does not increase the light radius).</description>
    <sheet>
      <description>Crystal heartglow lantern. Action: activate 20-ft bright / 20-ft dim light. Creatures can invest HP max (PB) to give the lantern that many charges (HP max returns after a rest). Deadbane mode: expend 1+ charges to detect undead within 20 ft for 1 hour (blue light, brighter when closer); each extra charge adds 30 minutes and +5 ft detect range.</description>
    </sheet>
    <setters>
      <set name="category">Magic Item</set>
      <set name="rarity">Uncommon</set>
      <set name="type">Wondrous Item</set>
    </setters>
  </element>

  <element name="Floodmote Heartglow Lantern" type="Magic Item" source="ToH" id="ID_ToH_ITEM_Floodmote_Heartglow_Lantern">
    <description>Fashioned from a single piece of specially grown hexagonal crystal in a metal frame, a heartglow lantern produces light without flame or fuel. While holding it, you can use an action to speak its command word, causing it to shed bright light in a 20-foot radius and dim light for an additional 20 feet until you end it with a bonus action or stop holding it.

Any creature touching the lantern can use an action to infuse it with vitality, reducing its hit point maximum by an amount equal to its proficiency bonus and granting that many charges to the lantern until the creature finishes a rest. A lantern can hold any number of charges from any number of creatures, but each creature can infuse it only once per long rest.

Floodmote. If you are submerged while holding or carrying this lantern, you can use a reaction and expend 1 or more charges to create a small bubble of air for yourself for 1 hour. For each charge beyond the first, the duration increases by 1 hour and you can choose one additional creature within 30 feet to gain a similar air bubble. Each bubble encloses only the head or breathing organ and provides breathable air for the duration.</description>
    <sheet>
      <description>Floodmote heartglow lantern. Functions like other heartglow lanterns for light and vitality charges. While submerged, reaction + 1+ charges: create an air bubble for yourself for 1 hour; each extra charge adds 1 hour and grants an additional bubble for a creature within 30 ft.</description>
    </sheet>
    <setters>
      <set name="category">Magic Item</set>
      <set name="rarity">Very Rare</set>
      <set name="type">Wondrous Item</set>
    </setters>
  </element>

  <element name="Tumblesafe Heartglow Lantern" type="Magic Item" source="ToH" id="ID_ToH_ITEM_Tumblesafe_Heartglow_Lantern">
    <description>Fashioned from a single piece of specially grown hexagonal crystal in a metal frame, a heartglow lantern produces smokeless light. While holding it, you can use an action to speak its command word and cause it to shed bright light in a 20-foot radius and dim light for an additional 20 feet until you end it as a bonus action or stop holding it.

Any creature touching the lantern can use an action to infuse it with vitality, reducing its hit point maximum by an amount equal to its proficiency bonus and granting that many charges to the lantern until the creature finishes a rest. The lantern can hold any number of charges from any number of creatures, but each creature can infuse it only once per long rest.

Tumblesafe. If you or a friendly creature you can see within 40 feet falls while you are holding or carrying this lantern, you can use a reaction and expend 1 or more charges to slow the fall. For each charge beyond the first, you can extend the light radius of the lantern by 5 feet. Each falling creature and object in the lantern's light descends at a rate of 60 feet per round and takes no damage from falling. They continue to descend at this rate until they land, even if they leave the light before landing.</description>
    <sheet>
      <description>Tumblesafe heartglow lantern. Normal heartglow light + vitality-charge rules. Reaction when a nearby ally/you falls: spend 1+ charges to make all creatures/objects in the light descend at 60 ft/round and take no falling damage until they land; extra charges extend the light radius by 5 ft each.</description>
    </sheet>
    <setters>
      <set name="category">Magic Item</set>
      <set name="rarity">Rare</set>
      <set name="type">Wondrous Item</set>
    </setters>
  </element>

  <!-- WEAPONS & COMPANION ITEMS -->

  <element name="Javelin of Teleportation" type="Magic Item" source="ToH" id="ID_ToH_ITEM_Javelin_of_Teleportation">
    <description>This short-hafted javelin bears a long metal head. You gain a +1 bonus to attack and damage rolls made with this magic weapon. When you hit a creature with it, you can speak its command word to force the target to make a DC 13 Wisdom saving throw. On a failed save, the target is teleported to an unoccupied space you can see within 60 feet of you that is on the ground or a floor.

The javelin's teleportation property can't be used again until the next dawn, but it remains a +1 javelin.</description>
    <sheet>
      <description>+1 javelin. On a hit, you can force the target (Wis DC 13) to teleport to an unoccupied space you can see within 60 ft on the ground/floor. Teleport feature recharges at dawn.</description>
    </sheet>
    <setters>
      <set name="category">Magic Weapons</set>
      <set name="rarity">Uncommon</set>
      <set name="type">Weapon</set>
    </setters>
  </element>

  <element name="Knight-Sergeant's Surcoat" type="Magic Item" source="ToH" id="ID_ToH_ITEM_Knight_Sergeant_s_Surcoat">
    <description>This long padded tabard of durable canvas and silk bears the colors and heraldry of a long-forgotten knightly order. While wearing it, you have advantage on Wisdom (Animal Handling) checks when interacting with horses, and advantage on Charisma (Persuasion) checks made to interact with humanoids of higher social rank than you (such as generals or monarchs).

Knight's Livery. While attuned to and wearing both the knight-sergeant's surcoat and the argent mantle, your Charisma score becomes 20. This has no effect if your Charisma is already 20 or higher.</description>
    <sheet>
      <description>Knight’s surcoat. Grants advantage on Animal Handling with horses and on Persuasion checks to higher-status humanoids. If attuned to this and an argent mantle, your Charisma becomes 20 (no effect if already 20+).</description>
    </sheet>
    <setters>
      <set name="category">Magic Item</set>
      <set name="rarity">Uncommon</set>
      <set name="type">Wondrous Item</set>
    </setters>
  </element>

  <element name="Medic's Sash" type="Magic Item" source="ToH" id="ID_ToH_ITEM_Medic_s_Sash">
    <description>This sash is designed for battlefield medics. While wearing it, your carrying capacity doubles. In addition, your movement doesn't provoke opportunity attacks if you are carrying a friendly creature that has 0 hit points or is dying.

First Aid. The sash has 3 charges. While wearing it, you can expend 1 charge as an action to cast spare the dying, or 2 charges as an action to cast cure wounds, using your Charisma modifier as your spellcasting modifier (minimum +1). The sash regains all expended charges at dawn.</description>
    <sheet>
      <description>Field medic’s sash. Doubles your carrying capacity, and you don’t provoke opportunity attacks while carrying an ally at 0 HP or dying. 3 charges/day: 1 charge to cast spare the dying, 2 charges to cast cure wounds (Cha-based).</description>
    </sheet>
    <setters>
      <set name="category">Magic Item</set>
      <set name="rarity">Uncommon</set>
      <set name="type">Wondrous Item</set>
    </setters>
  </element>

  <element name="Ninefold Swarmdagger" type="Magic Item" source="ToH" id="ID_ToH_ITEM_Ninefold_Swarmdagger">
    <description>You gain a +1 bonus to attack and damage rolls made with this magic dagger. When you hit a creature with it, you can use a bonus action to launch ghostly duplicates of the dagger at nearby foes. Spectral daggers fly at up to three creatures you can see within 30 feet of the original target. Make a ranged attack with this dagger against each target; on a hit, a target takes 1d4 force damage. Once a total of six creatures have been hit by these ghostly daggers, you can't use this property again until the next dawn.</description>
    <sheet>
      <description>+1 dagger. On a hit, bonus action: hurl spectral copies at up to 3 creatures within 30 ft of the target (ranged attack, 1d4 force on a hit). You can hit up to 6 creatures total with this effect per day; recharges at dawn.</description>
    </sheet>
    <setters>
      <set name="category">Magic Weapons</set>
      <set name="rarity">Rare</set>
      <set name="type">Weapon</set>
    </setters>
  </element>

  <element name="Paired Gauntlets of Striking" type="Magic Item" source="ToH" id="ID_ToH_ITEM_Paired_Gauntlets_of_Striking">
    <description>These leather gloves are reinforced with steel plates and decorated with images of two humanoids fighting side by side. While you and another creature are each wearing one of the gauntlets and are both within 5 feet of the same creature, you each have advantage on the first attack roll you make against that creature on each of your turns.</description>
    <sheet>
      <description>Partner’s gauntlets. If you and an ally each wear one and are both within 5 ft of the same foe, you both have advantage on the first attack you make against that creature on each of your turns.</description>
    </sheet>
    <setters>
      <set name="category">Magic Item</set>
      <set name="rarity">Uncommon</set>
      <set name="type">Wondrous Item</set>
    </setters>
  </element>

  <element name="Phase Arrow" type="Magic Item" source="ToH" id="ID_ToH_ITEM_Phase_Arrow">
    <description>When you make a ranged attack with this magic arrow, the attack ignores cover as the arrow briefly dips into the Plane of Shadow on its way to the target. If the target has full cover and you are aware that it is in a particular space, you can fire this arrow at that space with disadvantage on the attack roll.</description>
    <sheet>
      <description>Shadow-phase arrow. Ignores cover when fired. You can even shoot at a fully covered target if you know its space (with disadvantage).</description>
    </sheet>
    <setters>
      <set name="category">Ammunition</set>
      <set name="rarity">Uncommon</set>
      <set name="type">Arrow</set>
    </setters>
  </element>

  <element name="Potion Belt" type="Magic Item" source="ToH" id="ID_ToH_ITEM_Potion_Belt">
    <description>One or more thin bands of flexible pale blue crystal run along this plain brown leather belt. As an action, you can pour a potion onto a band, which absorbs the liquid and turns deep blue. Each band can store only one potion at a time.

This belt has one band. While wearing it, you can use an action to speak its command word and gain the benefits of the stored potion as though you had drunk it.</description>
    <sheet>
      <description>Belt with 1 crystal band. Action: pour a potion onto the band to store it. While worn, action + command word: gain the stored potion’s effects as if you drank it.</description>
    </sheet>
    <setters>
      <set name="category">Magic Item</set>
      <set name="rarity">Common</set>
      <set name="type">Wondrous Item</set>
    </setters>
  </element>

  <element name="Greater Potion Belt" type="Magic Item" source="ToH" id="ID_ToH_ITEM_Greater_Potion_Belt">
    <description>One or more thin bands of flexible pale blue crystal run along this plain brown leather belt. As an action, you can pour a potion onto a band, which absorbs the liquid and turns deep blue. Each band can store only one potion at a time.

This belt has three bands. While wearing it, you can use a bonus action to speak its command word and the name of one of the stored potions, gaining that potion's benefits as if you had drunk it.</description>
    <sheet>
      <description>Belt with 3 crystal bands. Action: load each band with a potion. While worn, bonus action + command word + potion name: gain that potion’s effects as if drunk.</description>
    </sheet>
    <setters>
      <set name="category">Magic Item</set>
      <set name="rarity">Rare</set>
      <set name="type">Wondrous Item</set>
    </setters>
  </element>

  <element name="Potion of Infinite Possibilities" type="Magic Item" source="ToH" id="ID_ToH_ITEM_Potion_of_Infinite_Possibilities">
    <description>This deep purple potion swirls with glittering flashes of red, green, and blue and smells faintly of ozone. For 1 hour after drinking it, you gain the following benefits:
• You have blindsight out to a range of 60 feet.
• When you roll a 1 on an ability check, saving throw, or attack roll, you can reroll the die and must use the new roll.
• You can see into the Ethereal Plane. Ethereal creatures and objects appear ghostly and translucent.

When the duration ends, you are stunned until the end of your next turn as your mind reels from the loss of these expanded perceptions.</description>
    <sheet>
      <description>Deep purple mind-warp potion. For 1 hour: 60-ft blindsight, reroll natural 1s on checks/saves/attacks, and see into the Ethereal Plane. When it ends, you are stunned until the end of your next turn.</description>
    </sheet>
    <setters>
      <set name="category">Magic Item</set>
      <set name="rarity">Very Rare</set>
      <set name="type">Potion</set>
    </setters>
  </element>

</elements>
